Guide to the Charles H. Sherrill Scrapbooks 1884-1937 MS 3191
New-York Historical Society
Charles H. Sherrill scrapbooks
1884-1937
New-York Historical Society
Sherrill, Charles Hitchcock, 1867-1936
MS 3191
13 Linear feet in 44 volumes
The collection consists of 44 scrapbooks (1884-1937) created by lawyer and diplomat Charles Hitchcock Sherrill (1867-1936). The scrapbooks contain ephemera,(including postcards, photographs, clippings, ribbons, pins, membership cards, and programs) as well as correspondence and drawings, all of which document Sherrill's education, work, travels, and interests, especially those related to sports and theater.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Arrangement
The bulk of the collection (Vol. 1-36) is arranged chronologically. The remaining volumes are arranged by subject.
Biographical / Historical
Charles Hitchcock Sherrill (1867-1936) was an American lawyer, diplomat, and sport officer.
Sherrill was born April 13, 1867 in Washington, DC to New York state politician and Washington lobbyist Charles H. Sherrill and Sarah Fulton Wynkoop Sherrill. He studied at Yale University, and was an accomplished college athlete, winning the inter-collegiate 100-yard dash title four times and the 220 yard dash three times. In 1888, he became the first person to use a crouch start in track and field sprints.
After graduating from Yale law school, Sherrill practiced law in New York City. He married George Barker Gibbs (1870-1947) in 1906, and they had one child, Gibbs Wynkoop Sherrill, born in 1908. Active in Republican politics, Sherrill coordinated some New York City campaign events for Presidents McKinley and Taft, and was appointed US Ambassador to Argentina from 1909 to 1910. He organized and was grand marshall of the 1916 Citizens Preparedness Parade, and during World War I, he was made Adjutant General of New York State, head of the New York National Guard. He later served as US Ambassador to Turkey from 1932 to 1933.
Outside of his work in law and politics, Sherrill's interests included travel, art, history, and sports. He wrote a number of books, on subjects ranging from diplomacy and world affairs, to stained glass, to his own family history. In one of his books, "The Purple or the Red" (1924), dedicated to Benito Mussolini, Sherrill argued for popular monarchy as an acceptable secondary option to republican government as a means to prevent the spread of Bolshevism.
Sherrill was an active participant in the social and civic life of New York City. He belonged to the Society of the Sons of the Revolution, and was a founding member of the National Arts Club. He was a member of social clubs such as the the Union League, the St. Nicholas Skating Club, the Grolier Club, and the Yale Club. He also helped coordinate the campaign to complete the building of NYC's Cathedral of St. John the Divine in the mid 1920s.
Sherrill's ardent enthusiasm for sports never waned. In 1892, he was elected to the Board of Directors of the New York Athletic Club. Active in Yale's Athletic and Alumni Associations, he helped organize the first Yale-Oxford Track Meet in 1894, and traveled to it annually, often serving as an official. From 1922 to his death, Sherrill was a member of the International Olympic Committee and played a vital role in organizing the 1932 Summer Olympics in Los Angeles. In 1935, during the preparations for the 1936 Summer Olympic Games in Berlin, Sherrill met twice with Hitler.
Sherrill died suddenly in France on June 25, 1936.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of George Gibbs Sherrill, 1937
Related Materials
The library contains a number of Sherrill's publications, including "The Sherrill Genealogy; the Descendants of Samuel Sherrill of East Hampton, Long Island, New York" and "My Story Book," an autobiography published posthumously in 1937.The Manuscripts Department also holds Mss Collection AHMC-Sherrill, Charles Hitchcock, which consists of a letter and an autograph.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 44 scrapbooks created by lawyer and diplomat Charles Hitchcock Sherrill (1867-1936). Covering the years 1884-1937, the scrapbooks contain clippings, correspondence, sketches, and ephemera (including postcards, photographs, ribbons, pins, membership cards, menus, and programs), all of which document Sherrill's work, social and political activities, travels, and interests.
Sports, politics, travel, civic and social events, art, and theater are common themes throughout Volumes 1-35, which are chronological records of Sherrill's life from his undergraduate years at Yale until his death. Volume 36 consists mainly of letters of condolence to Sherrill's widow, George Gibbs Sherrill, after Sherrill's death in Paris in 1936. Volumes 37 and 38 contain material related to Sherrill's genealogical research. Volumes 39-42 hold postcards from Sherrill's travels, including real photo postcards. Volume 43 contains mainly theater tickets and programs dated 1884-1888. Volume 44 is mostly blank, but does have a few hand-drawn cartoons (seemingly made by Sherrill as a child) and some other illustrations.
Most scrapbooks are labeled with dates and volume numbers.
Correspondence.; Photographs.; Postcards.; Scrapbooks.; Theater programs.; Ambassadors.; College sports -- United States.; Genealogy.; Lawyers -- New York (State) -- New York.; Olympics -- History.; Sports -- United States.
- Scrapbook 1, 1885-1888 (Offsite-box 1, Volume 1)
  Scope and Contents
  This volume documents Sherrill's Yale undergraduate years, including church services, rules and guidelines, fraternity life, athletics, dinners, and other events.
- Scrapbook 2, 1888-1889 (Offsite-box 1, Volume 2)
  This scrapbook covers Sherrill's senior year at Yale.
- Scrapbook 3, 1889-1890 (Offsite-box 2, Volume 3)
  This volume documents Sherrill's time at Yale Law School.
- Scrapbook 4, June 1890 - June 1894 (Offsite-box 2, Volume 4)
- Scrapbook 5, June 1894 - September 1895 (Offsite-box 3, Volume 5)
  This volume includes memorabilia from trips to England for Yale-Oxford sporting events. A clipping from Oxford dated July 10 reveals that Sherrill and a Yale colleague were arrested for setting off fireworks on the 4th of July.
- Scrapbook 6, September 1895 - August 1897 (Offsite-box 3, Volume 6)
  This volume documents Sherrill's membership in the Business Men's Republican and Sound Money Club and his support for President McKinley, including invitations to inaugural balls. It also contains an announcement of the formation of his law firm, Carmalt, Sherrill and Lockwood, accompanied by photographs of each man at his desk. In addition, there is some ephemera from Manhattan Beach and Brighton Beach seaside resorts.
- Scrapbook 7, August 1897 - January 1898 (Offsite-box 4, Volume 7)
- Scrapbook 8, January 1898 - July 1899 (Offsite-box 4, Volume 8)
- Scrapbook 9, July 1899 - May 1900 (Offsite-box 5, Volume 9)
- Scrapbook 10, May 1900 - January 1901 (Offsite-box 5, Volume 10)
- Scrapbook 11, January 1901 - October 1901 (Offsite-box 6, Volume 11)
- Scrapbook 12, October 1901 - August 1902 (Offsite-box 6, Volume 12)
- Scrapbook 13, August 1902 - May 1903 (Offsite-box 7, Volume 13)
- Scrapbook 14, May 1903 - September 1904 (Offsite-box 7, Volume 14)
- Scrapbook 15, September 1904 - November 1905 (Offsite-box 8, Volume 15)
- Scrapbook 16, November 1905 - August 1906 (Offsite-box 8, Volume 16)
- Scrapbook 17, August 1906 - July 1907 (Offsite-box 9, Volume 17)
- Scrapbook 18, July 1907 - July 1908 (Offsite-box 9, Volume 18)
- Scrapbook 19, July 1908 - May 1909 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 19)
- Scrapbook 20, May 1909 - July 1910 (Offsite-box 11, Volume 20)
  This scrapbook documents Sherrill's time as Ambassador to Argentina.
- Scrapbook 21, July 1910 - March 1912 (Offsite-box 11, Volume 21)
- Scrapbook 22, April 1912 - December 1912 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 22)
- Scrapbook 23, January 1913 - July 1914 (Offsite-box 12, Volume 23)
- Scrapbook 24, July 1914 - January 1916 (Offsite-box 13, Volume 24)
  The main subject of this volume is World War I.
- Scrapbook 25, January 1916 - May 1917 (Offsite-box 14, Volume 25)
- Scrapbook 26, May 1917 - January 1919 (Offsite-box 12, Volume 26)
  This volume focuses on Sherrill's appointment to Adjutant General of New York State, head of the NY National Guard.
- Scrapbook 27, January 1919 - September 1920 (Offsite-box 15, Volume 27)
  Labeled "Far East," this volume focuses on China, Korea, Japan, and the Phillipines. It also includes photos and ephemera from the Sherrill family's stopover in Hawaii.
- Scrapbook 28, September 1920 - January 1923 (Offsite-box 13, Volume 28)
- Scrapbook 29, January 1923 - January 1925 (Offsite-box 14, Volume 29)
- Scrapbook 30, January 1925 - February 1927 (Offsite-box 15, Volume 30)
- Scrapbook 31, February 1927 - August 1928 (Offsite-box 16, Volume 31)
- Scrapbook 32, August 1928 - June 1930 (Offsite-box 16, Volume 32)
- Scrapbook 33, June 1930 - October 1931 (Offsite-box 17, Volume 33)
- Scrapbook 34, October 1931 - October 1933 (Offsite-box 17, Volume 34)
  Labeled "Turkey," this volume focuses on Sherrill's time as Ambassador to Turkey.
- Scrapbook 35, October 1933 - 1936 (Offsite-box 18, Volume 35)
  This volume covers Sherrill's IOC activities regarding Jewish participation in the 1936 Berlin Olympics, including his interactions with Hitler and Nazi officials.
- Scrapbook 36, 1936-1937 (Offsite-box 19, Volume 36)
  This volume includes Sherrill's obituary, tributes, articles about his death, and letters of condolence addressed to his wife.
- Genealogy Scrapbook, 1902-1903 (Offsite-box 21, Volume 37)
- Genealogy Scrapbook, 1904-1906 (Offsite-box 20, Volume 38)
- Postcard Scrapbook - Argentina, Brazil, Portugal, and Spain, circa 1909-1910 (Offsite-box 22, Volume 39)
- Postcard Scrapbook - England, 1913 (Offsite-box 18, Volume 40)
- Postcard Scrapbook - England, circa 1913 (Offsite-box 22, Volume 41)
- Postcard Scrapbook - Germany, 1914 (Offsite-box 22, Volume 42)
- Theater Scrapbook, 1884-1888 (Offsite-box 19, Volume 43)
- Scrapbook of illustrations, undated (Offsite-box 19, Volume 44)
  includes miscellaneous illustrations, including a few hand-drawn cartoons.